1935年 伯恩茅斯
你好 伯恩茅斯 2353号
Hello. Bournemouth 2353.
是的 杰拉尔德·德雷尔是我的儿子
Yes, Gerald Durrell is my son.
格里
Gerry?
德雷尔太太...
Mrs Durrell...
你用藤条打了我儿子
You have just caned my son!
在法治社会 你会因打一个无辜的小孩
In a just society, you would be tied to a tree and whipped
而被绑树上鞭打的
for beating an innocent child!
他宁愿去板球馆喂老鼠
He would rather feed the rats
也不愿去教室上课
behind the cricket pavilion than attend his classes.
是啊 自从他来到
Yes, because he's been bullied,
这所破学校就一直被欺负
ever since arriving at this pitiful school!
你为什么会这么想呢 亲爱的
And why do you think that is, dear?
因为... 他有点不一样
Because... he's a bit different.
这就是为什么他会被欺负 你个白痴
That's why children are bullied, you moron.
他的粗鲁行为从何而来 显而易见
It's easy to see where his incivility comes from.
不要用那种词
Don't use that language!
别教育我 我不是你那些愚蠢的马屁精
Don't instruct me. I am not one of your witless flunkies.
无意冒犯 我相信你挺招人喜欢的
No offence, I'm sure you would be lovely...
如果你不用拍他马屁的话
if you were allowed to be.
教育的目的就是 引导出孩子最好的一部分
The purpose of education is to draw the best out of children,
而不是向他们灌输鞭打的恐惧
not to beat fear into them.
毫无疑问 有一位父亲的话
A father would no doubt
他们的缺点肯定会更少一点
have ironed out more of their shortcomings.
我期望看到一封道歉信
I look forward to a letter of apology.
他不会再回校了
Oh, he won't be returning.
我宁愿让猴子来教他
I'd rather he were taught by monkeys.
妈妈 我喜欢猴子来教 可以吗
Mum, I'd love that. Can we do that?
别犯蠢了 格里
Don't be daft, Gerry.
我有点不一样 是什么意思呢
What do you mean, I'm a bit different?
德雷尔的一家 第一季 第一集
你怎么能袖手旁观
How could you have stood by
让我去当个房地产经纪人呢
and let me become an estate agent?
我是个作家
I am a writer.
但是你也没在写东西啊 亲爱的
You don't actually write, though, do you, darling?
没错 我还是个时装模特呢
Yes, I'm a fashion model.
我是战斗机飞行员
Fighter pilot.
顺便说一下 我退学了
Oh, by the way, I've left school.
不 你没有
No, you haven't.
如果格里能退 我就能退
If Gerry can do it, so can I.
总之 我已经把校服拿到花园射穿了...
Anyway, I've taken my uniform into the garden and shot it, so...
我也要退学 我是榆木脑袋
I might as well leave too. I'm as thick as two short planks.
只要找到了老公 我就退学
As soon as I can find a husband, I'll be off.
你们都什么毛病
What is the matter with all of you?
罗杰
Roger?
来了 难教育的领着个难驯养的
Here he is, the unteachable leading the untrainable.
我们应该去科孚
We should go to Corfu.
我去过
I've been.
位于英国西南多塞特郡,是英国最令人忆及往昔的废墟之一
科"孚"堡 在他们装上屋顶之前
Corfu Castle. I'm not going back
我是不会再去的
till they put a roof on it.
那读科夫堡 亲爱的
It's Corfe Castle, darling.
天啊 马戈 不是吧 科孚是个希腊的小岛
Jesus, Margo! No, Corfu's a Greek island!
我说了我很笨
I told you I was dim.
亲爱的 你不笨
Darling, you are not dim!
你才十六岁 哪学来的什么老公
You're 16. What's all this about a husband?
我的朋友唐纳德住在科孚
My friend Donald lives in Corfu.
他说那里物价便宜 我能去那里搞写作
He says it's dirt cheap, so I can write there,
有好多恶心的动物给格里看 还有
full of disgusting animals for Gerry and,
莱斯利 你可以打猎
Leslie, you can shoot them.
- 嘿 马戈... - 我去收拾行李
- Hey, Margo... - I'll pack.
我们哪里都不去
We are not going anywhere.
我们不能逃避问题
We can't just run away from our problems.
下午好 德雷尔太太
Good afternoon, Mrs Durrell.
哦 叫我路易莎就好
Oh! Louisa, please.
确实 我们这些寡居的人就是要齐心
Indeed. We widowed folk must stick together.
你应该来我这喝点小酒的
You should come and have that sherry.
是啊 该来的
Yes, I should.
自从退休后 我经常打木球
Since I've retired, I've played a lot of bowls.
你打吗
Do you play?
要是我有时间...
If only I had the time...
还有球具的话
and the bowls.
我就直接一点吧
Let me speak plainly?
你我都是很有魅力的人
You are an attractive lady and I am an attractive man.
孩子们需要一个父亲...
The children need a father figure...
而且我很赞成住校
and I'm a big admirer of boarding schools.
过来
Come on!
水电气缴费通知
你好
Hello.
你怎么这么消沉
Why are you so miserable?
或许是因为 我是个好母亲
Perhaps it's because I thought I was a good mother
却成功地抚养出了一个难教育儿子
and yet all I've managed to do is bring up one unteachable son,
一个精神病 一个无知女儿和你
one psychopath, one vacuous daughter and you.
我又怎么了
What's wrong with me?
最糟糕的是 你们没一个看着是高兴的
And worse than that, none of you seems happy.
这栋房子里再也没有欢声笑语了
There's no laughter in this house any more.
一个作家不该开心 会适得其反的
A writer shouldn't be happy. It's counter-productive.
你不是作家 亲爱的 你就是个卖房的
You're not a writer, darling. You sell houses.
这只是挂羊头卖狗肉
It's a flag of convenience.
那你呢 如果鱼也喝酒的话
What about you? You drink like a fish,
你酒量大如海了
if fish drank gin.
我也知道我们经济困难
And I know we've got money problems.
这个家里没有秘密
There are no secrets in this family.
其实是有秘密的
There are secrets, actually.
天啊 你不会要死了吧
Oh, God, you're not dying, are you?
当然不是
No, I'm not dying.
秘密就是...
The secret is...
我不能再这样生活下去了
that I can't live like this any more.
当你们都还小的时候 我们就像是在旅游
When you were all small, it was like we were on a journey,
一直向前走
always moving forward.
现在我们停下了脚步
And now we've stopped moving forward
正在往下沉
and we are sinking.
所以有生以来第一次 拉里 我决定...
So, for once in my life, Larry, I have decided...
接受你的建议
to take your advice.
哪一个建议
Which advice?
你知道吗 这里的出租车
You know, a taxi would
可能跟伯恩茅斯的香蕉一个价钱
probably cost the same as a banana in Bournemouth.
都走了一半了 继续吧
We should start as we mean to go on.
想互相伤害吗
Wanting to kill each other?
省点钱
Economising.
看 我能看见村庄了
Look, I can see the village
在前面 你们看
up ahead. Look.
你没开玩笑吧
You are not serious.
听着 卖房子的钱才勉强付清我们的账单
Now, look, the house sale barely covered our debts.
我们身无分文
We have no money.
遗孀抚恤金就那么一点
I have a miserly widow's pension.
- 你是个小气的遗孀 - 闭嘴
- You are a miserly widow. - Be quiet!
你们可是一点钱都挣不到
And you all earn precisely nothing.
我们不是来度假的
We are not on holiday.
我们来这是像当地人一样
We are here to live like local people,
愉快地在一起生活
in joy and togetherness,
没有那些所谓文明的束缚
without the trappings of so-called civilisation,
文明 就我而言
which, as far as I can tell,
基本上就意味着残忍和异化
basically means cruelty and alienation.
一切都会很美好的
It's going to be wonderful.
不要跟他说话 再说 这里的人都说希腊语
Don't talk to him. Everybody here only speaks Greek, anyway.
- 嗨 你们要坐出租车吗 - 不要
- Hi. You peoples want a taxi? - No.
- 要 - 当然
- Yes. - Absolutely.
- 你们去哪里 - 我们喜欢走路
- Where are you going? - We like walking.
忽略她 我们要去
Ignore her. We're going
那边很远很远的宾馆
to that guesthouse in the far, far distance.
- 这车不错啊 - 美国产的
- That's a nice motor. - It's American.
在科孚可没有第二辆
Nothing like it on Corfu.
- 斯皮罗斯·哈利奇珀罗斯 - 莱斯利
- Spiros Halikiopoulos. - Leslie.
- 马戈 - 拉里
- Margo. - Larry.
我是... 德雷尔太太
I'm... Mrs Durrell.
母亲
The mother.
最重要的人
The most important person.
让我来拿包
I'll get your luggage.
- 格里在哪里 - 格里
- Where's Gerry? - Gerry?
- 有一只蜥蜴 - 树上有一只蜥蜴
- There's a lizard. - It's a tree with a lizard on it.
- 有什么好玩的 - 格里
- How could that possibly be interesting? - Gerry!
你们太白了
You's very pale.
是的 我们打算多做些日光浴
Yes, we plan to a lot of sunbathing.
不 我们不做
No, we don't.
这是我们来这里的主要目的
It's the main reason we came here.
不 才不是
No, it isn't.
- 你们要待多久 - 不知道
- How long are you staying? - We don't know.
但是 我们回英国也没有房子住了
But, well, we don't have a house to go back to in England.
说实话 如果我不是希腊人 我想当英国人
Honest to God, if I wasn't Greek, I'd like to be English.
谢谢你
Oh. Thank you.
一定就是这里了
Oh, this must be it.
不 你们不能住这里 太贵了
No, you don't stay here. Too expensive.
这岛上有好多空房子 我给你们找一幢
Lots of empty houses on the island. I'll find you one.
好啊 很好
Yes. Good.
德雷尔太太 过来
Mrs Durrell! Come!
格里 厕所里有个动物园
Gerry! There's a zoo in the lavatory!
我要睡在厕所里
I'm sleeping in the lavatory!
你带着这些东西居然能过海关
I can't believe the Customs let you through with those.
他们肯定能理解
I just think they know
在这个动荡的社会 自卫是多么重要
self-defence is vital in today's unsure world.
你应该和斯皮罗斯结婚
I think you should marry Spiros.
我不想再结婚了
I don't want to marry again.
而且他带着婚戒
But he was wearing a wedding ring...
他的仪表盘上
and he had a photograph
还放着他妻子和孩子的照片
of his wife and children on the dashboard.
那应该是希腊皇族的照片
I thought that was the Greek royal family.
为什么他会有他们的照片
Why would he have a photo of them?
- 灯在哪 - 科孚还没有通电
- Where's the? - Oh, there's no electricity on Corfu.
德雷尔太太 我拿到了更多的优惠
I get some more discounts, Mrs Durrells.
我们真的需要买些床
Ah, we really need to get some beds.
格里 穿上高筒靴
Gerry? Gerry? Wellingtons.
- 为什么 - 因为有蛇
- Why? - The snakes.
拿着
Here.
再穿上这个
Oh... and this.
- 什么 - 让你看起来更明显
- What? - So you can be seen.
- 妈妈 我保证会没事的 - 穿好了
- Mum, I'm sure it's fine. - There we are.
而且
And er....
别做危险的事
don't... do anything.
再见
Bye!
再见 妈妈
Bye, Mother. See you later.
马戈
Oh. Margo!
- 给我看看 - 看什么
- Show me. - What?
你知道的
You know what.
马戈 这里不是伯恩茅斯
Margo, this is not Bournemouth.
我知道 所以我们来这里了
I know. I presume that's why we're here.
希腊人都很保守的
The Greeks can be very conservative.
在我那个年代 年轻女士都应该避开太阳
In my day, young ladies avoided the sun.
在我的年代 就是现在 恰恰相反
Well, in my day, which is now, we don't.
书呢
Book?
好女孩 别拿它当枕头了
Good girl. And don't just use it as a pillow.
好了 开始写作
Right. Starting now.
终于开始了
At last.
莱斯利 亲爱的 你能帮我把...
Oh, Leslie, will you help me, darling, with the...
恐怕不行 我很忙
I'm afraid not. I'm too busy.
早上好
Erm... kalimera.
Kalimera.
说得很好 还会说其他的希腊语吗
That was excellent. Do you have any more Greek?
不会了 我们才来这里一天
No, we've only been here one day.
欢迎你
Oh. Welcome.
你以前见过他们吗
Have you seen one of those before?
- 没有 - 一个埃及秃鹫巢
- No. - The nest of an Egyptian vulture.
他们有个小节目 为了吃鸡蛋
Its party piece is breaking eggs it wants to eat
他们会用石头去砸
by throwing pebbles at them.
鸟类使用工具是非常罕见的
It's very rare for birds to use tools.
抱歉 你应该知道这点
Oh, sorry, you probably knew that.
不知道
No.
快走 快走 快
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
在汉普郡有金橘吗
Do you have kumquats in Hampshire?
没有 那主要产苹果
I don't think so. It's mainly apples...
和甘蓝
and cabbage.
在科孚 苹果可不收欢迎
Apples are not good in Corfu.
我们很确定 圣经中 夏娃就是被金橘所诱惑
We are pretty sure, in the Bible, Eve was tempted by a kumquat.
一个小玩笑
That's a tiny joke.
你的小动物们怎么样了
How are your creatures?
我迫不及待地想给家人看了
I can't wait to show my family.
我很喜欢你的乐观
Your optimism is impressive.
我很喜欢野生动物
I find my interest in wildlife
却被我朋友们认为太疯狂了
is regarded by my friends as a form of madness.
狗像袋鼠一样跳着走
Dogs jumping like kangaroos!
真好笑
Always funny.
莱斯利 好枪法
Good shot, Leslie.
注意别打伤你母亲
Don't hit your mother.
拉里 下来帮忙
Larry, come down here and help!
不行 我在工作
I can't. I'm working!
德雷尔太太
Mrs Durrells?
这是鲁格勒斯雅
I bring you Lugaretzia.
你好 为什么带她来
Hello. Why?
你需要帮助 一大家人
You need help. Big family,
漂亮的房子 但不够完美
house pretty, but not so perfect!
是的 你看出来了 谢谢你
Yes, you spotted that. Well, Thank you,
但是我们负担不起 斯皮罗斯
Spiros, but we can't afford help.
你当然可以 你是英国人
Of course you can. You're English.
英国人也有很多种
The English come in all kinds,
但我们是穷的那种
and we are the poor type.
她价格低 又是兼职 几乎免费
She's cheap. Part-time, almost free.
天啊 我看起来像个老太婆
Oh, God, I look like some kind of a witch.
不 哪有 德雷尔先生在哪
No, you don't. Where's Mr Durrells?
他去世了 自私地先走了
Oh, he's dead... selfishly.
所以就剩我一个人 肩负重担
So it's just me now, shouldering the burden.
像驴一样 当妈又当爸
Like a braying, sexless donkey!
她听不懂英语
She doesn't understand English,
所以你想这么跟她抱怨都行
so you can shout out bad things about her.
我不想对她大喊大叫
I don't want to shout out bad things about her.
- 她有多便宜 - 鲁格勒斯雅
- How cheap is she? - Lugaretzia...
约为人民币3角钱
一天十五德拉克马
15 drachmas a day.
欢迎你
Welcome.
她有点疑心病
Erm... she's a little bit hypochondriac.
再见 德雷尔太太
Goodbye, Mrs Durrells.
亲爱的 发生什么了
Oh, darling, what's the matter?
一个男人对我大吼大叫
A man shouted at me.
亲爱的
Oh, sweetheart.
没事 只是
It's all right. It's just
和我期待的不一样
going to be more different than I thought.
是的
Yes.
我也是
Yes, me too.
妈妈需要性生活
别这么软弱 冲他喊回去
Don't be so feeble. Go back and shout at him!
什么 那他就有借口把我扔到海里或者杀死我
What, so he has an excuse to throw me into the sea or kill me?
- 拿点道德勇气出来 - 你们俩别吵了
- Oh, have some moral courage. - Stop it, you two.
不管那是什么勇气 你有过那玩意吗
When have you ever shown any moral courage? Whatever that is.
我每天都在我的作品里展示这种勇气
I show moral courage in my writing every day.
什么作品 找一个正经的工作吧
What writing?! Get a proper job!
直译为有智商的侏儒
你这个低能儿
You're an intellectual dwarf.
拉里 这么说太粗鲁了
Larry, that is cruel.
至少我有智商
At least I'm intellectual.
你的智商只是侏儒的等级
Your intellect is dwarf-sized!
天哪
For God's sake.
是的 很漂亮对吧 这是我母亲的
Yes, it's very nice, isn't it? It was my mother's, actually.
好像有一个子弹孔 莱斯利一定是冲她开枪了
It looks like a bullet hole. Leslie must have nearly shot her.
她不会还在讲那事吧
She's not still going on about that, is she?
不
No!
鲁格勒斯雅
Lugaretzia?
鲁格勒斯雅 回来
Lugaretzia? Come back!
莱斯利 你差点杀了她
Leslie, you could have killed her.
这是气枪 最多就是点轻伤
It's an airgun. She could get a flesh wound at worst...
- 或者少只眼睛 - 或者少只眼睛
- or lose an eye! - Or lose an eye?!
不可置信 我像个奴隶一样照顾你们
Unbelievable! I have been working like a slave for you.
你却让我失去了唯一的帮手
Now we've lost my only bit of help.
树林里有好多动物啊
There's so many species in the wood.
- 我找到了... - 格里
- I found... - Oh Gerry!
- 抓住它们 - 把他们赶出去 赶出去
- Stop them! - Get them out! Get them out!
不要踩它们
Don't stamp on them!
- 让我开抢打它们 - 不要开抢
- Let me shoot one of them! - Don't shoot them!
停下来
Stop it!
都别吵了
我做错什么了
Where did I go wrong?
你们怎么都变得这么招人厌
How did you all become so vile?
你知道她的问题是什么吗
You know what her problem is?
不应该是我们有问题吗
Don't you think we're the problem?
- 不 - 别傻了
- No. - Don't be absurd.
她需要个男人
She needs a man.
你怎么敢这样说妈妈 我会照顾她的
Don't you dare talk about Mother like that. I'll look after her.
我借你本弗洛伊德的书吧 叫《恋母情结》
Let me lend you a paper by Freud called the Oedipus Complex.
你也就耍耍嘴皮子 可没人在乎
I expect that's really clever, but nobody cares.
身体是为性而生
The body is built for sex.
格里都知道 他见过动物交配
Gerry knows. He watched animals mating.
你太迷恋性了
You are obsessed with sex.
我们终于达成了共识
At last, we agree on something.
虽然我没有任何经验 但至少可以帮妈妈一把
And since I'm not getting any, at least we can help Mother.
我们应该从哪开始呢
All right, where should we start looking?
总不能从街上随便抓个男人吧
We can't just drag men in off the street.
下午好
Good afternoon.
- 西奥 - 我是西奥·史蒂芬奈兹
- Theo! - My name is Theo Stephanides.
- 你好 - 下午好
- Hello. - Good afternoon.
格里邀请我来喝茶
Gerry kindly invited me for tea.
- 希望你能有更多的探索 - 非常感谢
- For your future discoveries. - Thank you so much.
- 茶 没错 - 我要改天再来吗
- Tea, yes. - Shall I come back another day?
- 不 不 不 - 别走
- No, no, no. - It's fine.
- 茶 - 西奥
- Tea... - Theo?
你单身吗
Are you single?
当然 是的 我是
Yes. Yes, I am.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
我们不知道怎么烧开水
We couldn't work out how to heat the water.
别担心 我随时都能喝茶
Oh, don't worry. I can have tea any time.
无花果拌沙丁鱼 这才是新东西
Figs with sardines -- that's breaking new ground.
那么 关于科孚 你们想知道点什么吗
So, can I help unlock any mysteries about Corfu?
你能解释一下 我晒日光浴的时候
Can you explain why a monk shouted at me
为什么有个疯僧侣对我大吼大叫
like a lunatic as I was sunbathing?
也许你只是躺在他的地盘上了
Maybe you were just lying in his space.
以前希腊人半辈子都裸着
The Greeks used to spend half their lives naked.
所以他可没有借口
So he has no excuse.
那是古代希腊人 而且是男性裸体
That was the Ancient Greeks and male nudity.
女性身体通常都是有部分衣物遮盖的
Female bodies were more often shown partially clothed.
那就很清楚了
Well, there you go, then.
要么成为男人 要么在比基尼上穿外套
Become a man or wear a coat over your bikini.
对待男人和女人的规矩是不一样的吗
There's one rule for men and one for women, isn't there?
你刚刚才注意到吗
Have you only just noticed?
我一直在忙着长大
I've been busy growing up.
这种事存在多久了
How long has this been going on?
哪怕是伟大的亚里士多德
Even Aristotle, who was no slouch,
都视女性低男性一等
placed women some way below men...
但还是比奴隶地位要高的 万岁
but above slaves. Hurrah!
还有饼干吗 马戈
Are there any more biscuits, Margo?
自己去拿
Get them yourself!
那么 西奥
So, Theo...
你还没有结婚
you are not married yet.
你喜欢什么样的女人
What do you look for in a woman?
能和我交流想法的人
Someone I can exchange ideas with,
既能探讨科学发展
discuss scientific advances
也能无言对坐
and just sit quietly with.
- 不行 那没办法了 - 没戏
- Yeah, no, that won't work. - No.
西奥来喝了茶
Theo came for tea.
算不上茶 但他给了我个笼子
Well, not tea, but he gave me this,
我把睡鼠放了进去
which I filled with dormice.
格里
Oh, Gerry.
我们告诉莱斯利 他不准再在房子附近练枪了
We told Leslie he can't shoot near the house any more
打扰了拉里写作 而且可能会射死我们
because Larry can't write and he might kill us.
所以他明天要到岛的另一头去
So he's going off round the island tomorrow.
过来
Come on.
你长大了啊 对吧
Ooh! Getting quite big, aren't you?
是啊 我要不要下来
Yes. Should I get off?
不用
No.
你现在可以下来了 我腿麻了
You can get off now. I can't feel my legs.
有什么建议吗
Any recommendations?
别吃东西
Hm... Avoid the food.
光喝酒就行
Stick to the booze.
外国人啊 是吗
A fellow foreigner, huh?
是的
Yes,
不过我认为自己是世界公民
although I consider myself a citizen of the world.
你看上去似乎游历四方啊
You look like you've been around.
航行过七大洋
Sailed the seven seas.
有没有最喜欢的
Do you have a favourite?
没一个喜欢的
Hated all of them!
危险 寒冷
Treacherous, cold...
潮湿
wet.
缺女人
Generally devoid of women.
我穿的完全没问题
I am dressed perfectly respectably,
不像别人口中的古代希腊男人
unlike Ancient Greek men, from all accounts.
我有权躺在这里
And I'm entitled to be here.
我想你应该先别去晒日光浴了
I think you should take a break from sunbathing...
我肯定要去的
I am not going to be put off...
因为你的脸都晒成西红柿了
because your face looks like a tomato.
激动人心的大新闻
Exciting news!
为什么你说话这么轻 你从来不小声说话
Why are you speaking quietly? You never speak quietly.
因为我不想让妈妈听见
Because I don't want mother to hear.
天啊 为什么每个人都傻傻的
God, why is everyone so dim?
她去银行了 看看钱有没有到账
She's gone to the bank to see if the money's arrived yet.
很幸运 今天不会饿肚子 我打到了这个小美人
Fortunately, we won't starve. I've shot this beauty.
如果这个顶饱的话 她就不需要钱了
She won't need her own money if this works out.
我给她找了个男人
I've found her a man.
- 不是吧 谁 - 他的名字是克里奇船长
- No? Who? - His name's Captain Creech.
幽默感十足 有许多故事可讲
Cracking sense of humour. Stories to tell.
说话不兜圈子 而且他肯定还有点钱
Doesn't beat about the bush and, well, he must have a few quid.
这事肯定会搞砸的
This will go horribly wrong, you know.
- 你怎么撮合他们 - 可能要先等几个星期
- How will you get them together? - I might leave it a few weeks.
她大姨妈要来了 会有点喜怒无常
Her monthly's coming up and she'll be more volat...
别说这种事了 你真是...
Stop saying these things! You are such a...
卖家具的钱到了
The money's arrived from the sale of our furniture.
钱不多 但是
It's not much, but it
我们可以过得更舒服一点了
might make us feel a bit more like we belong.
给教徒抽的
For Easter.
- 不客气 - 谢谢
- Parakalo. - Efharisto.
感觉怎么样 妈妈
How are you feeling, mother?
高兴多了
Well... happier.
还是气你把鲁格勒斯雅吓走了
Still livid that you drove Lugaretzia away.
荷尔蒙呢
And... hormonally?
别瞎扯了
Don't be ridiculous!
我今晚要带一个朋友来吃晚饭
I'm bringing a pal over for supper tonight.
碰巧和你同龄
Your age, as it happens.
我们第一位客人
Well, our first guest.
我要做什么呢 主要食材只能是无花果
What shall I cook? It will have to be mainly figs.
好吧 我今天要出去
Right, I'm off for the day.
有没有人注意到莱斯利变了
Did anyone notice anything different about Leslie?
我尽量不看他
I try not to look at him.
- 他变帅了好多 - 可没有
- He is becoming very handsome. - He really isn't.
他没带枪就走了
He left without a gun.
我从来都没见过他不带枪
I've never seen him without a gun.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
我今天早上没带枪
I didn't take a firearm
因为我已经不玩那个了
this morning because I'm over all that now.
太好了 莱斯利
Oh. Oh, I'm so glad, Leslie.
我只是喜欢在小岛上探索
I just like exploring the island,
带着字典 和当地人聊天
you know, with a dictionary. Talking to the locals.
到底是怎么了 你是不是杀人了
What's really going on? Have you shot someone dead?
别傻了 马戈
Don't be silly, Margo.
他只是长大了
He's just growing up.
再说 都已经是一九三几年了 亲爱的
Besides, it's the 1930s, darling.
人们已经不需要枪了
People don't need guns any more.
妈妈 这是克里奇船长
Mother, this is Captain Creech.
他一直期盼见到你
He's been looking forward to meeting you.
德雷尔太太
Well... Mrs Durrell.
你这样美丽的脸庞 应该站在船头才对
With a face like that, you should be on the front of a ship.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
乔迁的礼物
A present for the house...
牙买加最好的朗姆酒
a bottle of the finest rum from Jamaica.
你有没有去过牙买加
Have you er... ever been to Jamaica?
不 不 我没有
No, no, I haven't.
我第一次得淋病的地方
The first place I ever caught gonorrhoea.
所以 我们就在那了
So... there we were,
甲板下一群乌拉圭的妓女
a dozen Uruguayan strumpets below deck
从地球的屁眼里喷涌出一阵狂风
and a ripping wind, straight out of the arsehole of the Earth.
这真的太美味了
My, this is good tucker.
我喜欢女孩子
I like a girl who is er...
在厨房里得心应手
handy in the galley,
在床上也是一样
as well as in bed.
- 我说到哪了 - 地球的屁眼
- Where was I? - Arsehole of the Earth.
好了 这个故事说得差不多了
Yes, that's quite enough of that story.
格里 给我们唱首歌 随便什么都行
Gerry, sing us a song. Anything you like.
head主要是头部的意思
- 厕所在哪 - 此时此刻 正嗡嗡作响
- Where's your head? - At the moment, it's pounding.
这是航海用语
It's nautical for...
屎坑 茅厕
Crapper, dunny,
雷鸣桶
thunder box.
- 他应该是指厕所 - 是的
- I think he means the lavatory. - Yes.
是的 我现在知道了
Yes, I know that... now.
房子后面
It's round the back.
失陪
Excuse me.
你到底在干什么
What the hell did you think you were doing?
把那种肮脏的色老头带到家里来
Bringing that filthy old lecher into our house.
咱家不常来这种客人
He's a breath of fresh air.
女人让男人当家就会发生这种事
This is what happens when women let men rule the roost.
起来
Get up!
- 再见 - 莱斯利
- Bye. - Oh, Leslie.
你今天要做什么
What are you doing today?
就到处走走 和当地人聊天
Just walk around, chat with locals.
打听一下工作 好资助一下家里
Ask for work, so I can help out with the money.
- 他在说谎 - 我知道
- He's lying. - I know.
我只是想像对待大人一样对他
I just thought I'd treat him like an adult.
你允许他有好几把枪时
What were you treating him
是把他当什么对待的
like when you let him have half a dozen guns?
我是个母亲 不是警察
I'm a mother, not a policeman.
那也许能让他自律一点
I thought it might lead to some discipline,
让他即使没有父亲 也能成为男子汉
make a man of him, with Daddy not being there.
当你有了孩子 你就会发现...
You'll discover, if ever you have children...
你说吧 我要去一下院子里
I am listening. I'm just going into the garden.
蠢家伙 跑哪去了
Stupid boy, where are you?
妈的见鬼...
Sodding, bloody...
拉里 注意用词
Larry, please!
著名英国女作家 两次世界大战期间伦敦文学界核心人物
我敢肯定弗吉尼亚·伍尔芙不会满口脏话
I'm sure Virginia Woolf doesn't swear like a trooper.
她弟弟也没把她打字机上的X键拆掉
Well, her brother didn't remove the letter X from her typewriter.
莱斯利为什么要那样做
Why would Leslie do that?
这样我就没法写"性"这个字了
So I don't write the word "sex" so much, apparently.
行吧 我会以牙还牙的
It's all right. I'll get him back.
我有没有说过 你的屁股应该放在船头
Did I mention that your arse should be on the front of a ship?
别再提了 我们昨晚听得够多了
Don't start that again. We had quite enough last night.
都怪你们让我喝酒
It's your fault for letting me drink.
追本溯源
Look below the surface
通常都是女人惹的祸
it's usually the ladies that cause the problems.
听着 我很惊讶你怎么现在还活着
Look, I am astonished that nobody has murdered you yet.
现在请你离开
Now, please leave!
你给我弄点午饭 我就走
After you've made me a spot of lunch.
别吵了 用该死的铅笔吧
Shut up! Use a bloody pencil!
鲁格勒斯雅
Lugaretzia!
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
你不在简直天下大乱
It's been hell without you.
狗"酿"养的
Son of a bitz.
我看到斯皮罗斯一直在教你
I see Spiros has been teaching you.
在英国 我们会骂"杂种"
In England, we say "bastard".
杂"肿"
Barsto?
- 杂种 - 杂"肿"
- Bastard. - Barsto.
我爱它 妈妈
I love him, Mum.
格里 把它放外面
Oh, Gerry, take it outside.
格里 马上把它弄外面去
Gerry, take him outside, now!
- 它会跑了的 - 这么一会 跑不了的
- He'll escape. - Not for a while, he won't.
- 格里 - 还有好多没研究到呢
- Gerry? - There's so much to see.
吃了就走吧
Eat, then leave.
如果让你失望了 非常抱歉
I'm sorry if I've disappointed you.
我和粗人们混得太久了
I've spent too much time in the company of uncouth men.
好吧
Oh. Well...
谢谢
thank you.
抱歉 我...
I'm sorry, I...
滚
Get out!
行吧 我吃完了就走
Fine. I'll just finish my lunch.
不走的话...
Now, you leave...
我就开枪了
or I'll shoot you.
你不会的
No, you won't.
你真是太欠教训了
You are in great need of a slap!
那你就可以开枪打人了吗
Oh, so it's OK for you to shoot and nearly kill someone?
没错 正是
Yes. Yes, it is.
莱斯利 我们跟你说了 不准再开枪了
Leslie, we told you, no more shooting!
不是我
It wasn't me!
你给我做媒的事
That is the last time you
到此为止 明白了吗
try to find me a husband. Is that clear?
你确定吗 我在镇上酒吧
Are you sure? I met a fascinating Turk
认识了一个特别迷人的土耳其人
in a bar in town.
你怎么觉着我会喜欢
And how did you think I would fall for...
一个见鬼的大力他妈的水手呢
Popeye the bloody Sailor Man?!
他也不是"我这个岁数的"
And he's not "my age"!
我们觉的性生活会让你平静下来
We think the sex will calm you down.
天哪
God!
你们父亲是我一生所爱
Your father was the love of my life,
我不想要 也不需要一个远逊于他的替代品
and I don't want or need a pale imitation of him.
真可悲
Well, I find that rather sad.
你或许已经放弃了...
You may have given up...
可我们还没有
but we haven't.
你跑哪去了
Oh, where have you been?
我去跟着莱斯利 结果迷路了
I was following Leslie and I got lost.
我想问问路 就能走回来
I tried to ask the way home,
但没人想过要学点英语
but nobody's bothered to learn English.
总之 莱斯利不爱玩枪了
Anyway, Leslie's lost his interest in guns
是因为他找了个女朋友
because he's got a girlfriend.
找了啥
A what?
我看到他跟一个本地女孩在一起
I found him with a local girl,
还亲来抱去的
kissing and worse.
或许来这里是来对了
Well, maybe it was a good idea to come out here after all.
我只是提了提要找男朋友
I mention wanting a boyfriend,
你就说我愚不可及 饥渴难耐
and you call me empty-headed and sex-mad.
但轮到莱斯利找到女朋友 他就成了大英雄
But Leslie finds someone, and he's a hero?
首先 马戈 我很激动你想到了自己
Firstly, Margo, I am thrilled that you are thinking for yourself
- 还强调了双重标准 - 谢谢
- and highlighting double standards. - Thank you.
其次...
And secondly...
不要对你妈妈如此不礼貌
don't you dare be so bloody rude to your mother.
行吧 那我还是给自己找个男人去吧
Good, I'll find myself a man, then.
嗨 鲁格 很高兴你回来了
Hello, Luga. Glad you're back.
这短篇简直天才之作
This short story is genius.
- 谁写的 - 我
- Oh? Who wrote it? - Me.
看看谁回来了
Look who I find walking home!
妈
Mum.
格里 家里有一只蜘蛛 两只睡鼠
Gerry, you have a spider, two dormice,
一只乌龟 还有一大家子人
a tortoise and a family.
你不能再弄一只鹈鹕
You do not need a pelican.
- 放了吧 - 等我研究完了就放
- Let it go. - I will after I've studied it.
这不好笑 斯皮罗斯
It's not funny, Spiros.
当然不
No, of course not.
来吧 格里 我们来弄个动物园的笼子
Come on, Gerry, we'll make a zoo cage!
拉里 我们有必要谈谈你的作品
Larry, we need to talk about your writing.
偷窥这事回头再说
We'll deal with you being a peeping Tom later.
抱歉你不喜欢它 但我拒绝...
I'm sorry you don't like it, but I refuse to let...
不 写得很好
No, it's brilliant.
但这里面母亲形象为何如此可怕
But why is the mother so horrible?
一切与您无关
Everything isn't about you.
与我无关
Oh, nothing is about me.
我的人生完全耗费在了孩子们身上
My life is devoured by my children.
二十一年中我从未
In 21 years I haven't thought
连续五分钟想着自己的
about myself for five consecutive minutes.
这故事很好 是不是
But it's good, isn't it?
你喜欢那个结尾吗
Did you like the ending?
喜欢 拉里 写得很不错
Yes, Larry, it's very good.
你会让我们骄傲的
You're going to make us very proud.
让全家骄傲
In this family?
至少可以让我们以一种复杂方式稍微开心一点
You're going to make us mildly pleased in a complicated way.
来看这个
Come and look at this.
礼拜堂旁边那些石头
The rocks, just by the chapel.
真是我的女孩
That's my girl.
您好
Hello!
您是德雷尔太太吗
Mrs Durrell?
我是西奥多尔·史蒂芬奈兹
Theodore Stephanides.
很高兴终于见到您
Delighted to finally meet you.
我觉得你们还需要一根斜梁
I suspect you need a cross-piece there.
这里
Here.
我记得叫做... 桁条
I believe it's called erm... a purlin.
莱斯利 你新交的女朋友叫什么
Leslie, what's your new girlfriend's name?
你怎么知道的
How do you know about her?
亲爱的 我什么都知道 我可是你妈
I know everything, darling. I'm your mother.
她叫亚历克西娅
She's called Alexia.
真是全天下最可爱的名字
It's the loveliest name.
而如果打出她的全名
And if you ever want to type it,
就得把X键还给拉里
you'll have to give Larry his X back.
我的女孩
To koritsi mou,
亚历克西娅是...
i Alexia einai...
莱斯利
Leslie!
斯皮罗斯 你为什么对我们这么好
Why are you so good to us, Spiros?
我们没钱 还总是在吵架
We have no money. We argue all the time.
我们有个说法 叫"普世之爱"
We have a word, philoxenia.
意思是"对陌生人的关爱"
It means "love to strangers".
这词真棒
That is so sweet.
而且很明显你需要帮助
And it's clear you need help.
妈的见鬼
Sodding, bloody!
鲁格勒斯雅 这个在希腊语里面怎么说
Lugaretzia, how do you say this in Greek?
这是回敬你的 莱斯利
That is my revenge on you, Leslie.
用枪摆成一个X
以X还X
An X for an X.
我只是让它们看起来没那么暴力了
I just made them look less violent!
有人住这吗
Does anyone live here?
有人过世了吗
Somebody died?
这是我的朋友唐纳德和马克斯
My friends Donald and Max.
我请他们来的
I invited them over.
天哪 这是谁
Gosh, who's this?